<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-03T09:29:00+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Oxfordshire &lt;br /&gt;Community &lt;br /&gt;Land Trust</title><entry><title type="html">Planning application submitted for Dean Court</title><link href="/2019/02/21/planning-application-submitted-for-dean-court.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Planning application submitted for Dean Court" /><published>2019-02-21T14:05:05+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-21T14:05:05+00:00</updated><id>/2019/02/21/planning-application-submitted-for-dean-court</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/02/21/planning-application-submitted-for-dean-court.html">&lt;p&gt;We’re delighted to say we have now submitted our planning application for the new flats in Dean Court (Reference Number P19/V0424/FUL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details can be found at:&lt;br /&gt;
http://www.whitehorsedc.gov.uk/java/support/Main.jsp?MODULE=ApplicationDetails&amp;amp;REF=P19/V0424/FUL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please let us know if you have any questions about this.  Comments can also be made to the District Council. It’s a very exciting moment for us as we finally look forward to the next stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s also time to start finding prospective tenants. Do you know anyone who might be interested?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People who are interested in living here must:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be registered with www.whitehorsehomechoice.org.uk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must have a strong local connection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must have a housing need&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Must be interested in cooperating with other tenants to help run the project as effectively as possible*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone who meets these criteria ask them to make sure that they are registered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;* full training and support will be given to tenants to do this. Details will be developed in collaboration with the successful tenants. It could involve co-running the car share scheme, ensuring the grounds and shared spaces are well looked after, or making sure the shared bins are put out. Please note that it is not expected that tenants would undertake repairs or rent collection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="community land trust" /><category term="dean court" /><category term="co-operative housing oxford" /><category term="community-led housing" /><category term="collaborative housing" /><category term="oxfordshire community land trust" /><summary type="html">We’re delighted to say we have now submitted our planning application for the new flats in Dean Court (Reference Number P19/V0424/FUL).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/Untitled-1.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">January Update</title><link href="/2019/01/25/january-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="January Update" /><published>2019-01-25T14:53:20+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-25T14:53:20+00:00</updated><id>/2019/01/25/january-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/01/25/january-update.html">&lt;p&gt;Belated greetings for 2019. It’s been a long time since we were in touch but we think the news today will more than make up for the long period of silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dean-court-update&quot;&gt;Dean Court Update&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you will remember what a devastating blow it was when we had to suspend the Dean Court project in March 2015 because we’d hit an unexpected legal issue with the Charity Commission. Back then we had to let go of the almost £1m worth of funding we had assembled, including a hefty grant from the Government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the delay has in fact taken a positive guise as we have been able to take advantage of the new Community Housing Fund 2018, a £163m pot for exactly the sort of thing we are doing at Dean Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In November we heard that we’d been successful in being awarded £67,000 by Homes England towards the pre-development work on the Dean Court site&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as the money arrives we will be applying for planning permission for the Dean Court flats. In parallel with preparing new plans we’ve been working with our lawyers to sort out the access to the site which is owned by Vale of White Horse District Council.  We hope this will also be concluded to our mutual satisfaction in the very near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/181114 - FullSlideDeck.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;event-in-february&quot;&gt;Event in February&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know anyone who might be interested in forming a group to ultimately find or create a community-led place in which to live affordably and securely? We’re running a meeting for such people on Tuesday 12th February 6pm (for an hour) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://openhouseoxford.co.uk&quot;&gt;Open House Oxford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;funding-for-office&quot;&gt;Funding for office&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calling it an office is a bit grand: we have in fact got a hot-desk and we’re there every Tuesday and at other times by arrangement. Just before Christmas, we heard that the Midcounties Co-op will fund our rent at &lt;a href=&quot;http://makespaceoxford.org&quot;&gt;Makespace Oxford&lt;/a&gt; until the end of Feb 2020 so that’s very good news and a welcome boost after the years of running on empty! OCLT board meetings are held here every month&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;updateon-the-hub&quot;&gt;Update on the hub&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OCLT are collaborating with a range of partners to set up a housing hub to promote and develop community-led projects across the Thames Valley. It’s called Collaborative Housing. Next month we will be applying for funding to start supporting groups so &lt;a href=&quot;https://collaborativehousing.us18.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=cad5092a6194557f4e0cd18ba&amp;amp;id=69ef08d93a&quot;&gt;sign up to the mailing list&lt;/a&gt; if you want to keep informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally a further big thanks to the donors who made it possible for us to employ the redoubtable John Bloxsom who has been the engine of much of this progress. Thanks again to them but most of all to him. The Homes England money will mean we can fund him for a bit longer so that’s a brilliant result.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Belated greetings for 2019. It’s been a long time since we were in touch but we think the news today will more than make up for the long period of silence.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/20171005_202215-1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">New report on Community-led housing in Oxford City</title><link href="/2019/01/23/report2019.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New report on Community-led housing in Oxford City" /><published>2019-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2019/01/23/report2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/01/23/report2019.html">&lt;p&gt;In March 2017, Oxford City Council received £54,859 from the Community Housing Fund to support the promotion and delivery of more community-led housing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oxford City Council commissioned the &lt;a href=&quot;http://COLLABORATIVEHOUSING.ORG.UK&quot;&gt;Collaborative Housing Hub&lt;/a&gt;, which is a partnership between Community First Oxfordshire, Oxfordshire Community Foundation and Oxfordshire Community Land Trust, to undertake a research project to explore how community housing could be delivered sustainably within Oxford City. The methods used for this study included a combination of desk research, a needs assessment, interviews, outreach events and financial assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are viable models which will work in Oxford’s urban fabric from small scale (shared co-operative houses and tiny windfall sites) to large partnership development where citizen-leadership can bring distinct benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;https://issuu.com/cohohub/docs/oxfordclh_finalreport_and_appendice&quot;&gt;Read the full report here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some key recommendations from the report:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a strategy to enable genuinely affordable community-led approaches in Oxford and promote community-led housing within the Oxfordshire Growth Board and Joint Statutory Spatial Plan.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apply to the Community Housing Fund (grant) to provide enabling support within the council for community-led housing schemes that are currently being proposed by groups in Oxford.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include support for community-led housing in the Local Plan, housing and tenancy strategies, appoint a Councillor as Oxford’s community-led housing champion, and require larger sites to include a proportion of community-led housing through Section 106 agreements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up a revolving loan fund that community-led housing groups can access for cheaper finance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outreach for this study showed that very few people know about community-led housing solutions despite having many benefits which struck a chord with interviewees and focus groups including genuine affordability in perpetuity, individual well-being and supportive neighbourhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The members of the study team were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brookes.ac.uk/templates/pages/staff.aspx?uid=p0070247&quot;&gt;Dr Sue Brownill&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Fisher_Charlie&quot;&gt;Charlie Fisher&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ron-gibbons-6361a311/&quot;&gt;Ron Gibbons&lt;/a&gt; (Oxfordshire Community Land Trust), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tom-mcculloch-090a9061/&quot;&gt;Tom McCulloch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/fiona-mullins-82b91a39/&quot;&gt;Fiona Mullins&lt;/a&gt; (Community First Oxfordshire) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaynewoodley/?originalSubdomain=uk&quot;&gt;Jayne Woodley&lt;/a&gt; (Oxfordshire Community Foundation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important contributions to the assessment were made by Oxford City Council, Savills, &lt;a href=&quot;www.transitionbydesign.org&quot;&gt;Transition by Design&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/jimm-reed-4b782723/&quot;&gt;Jimm Reed&lt;/a&gt; (CoHo Ltd), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephenhillfutureplanning/&quot;&gt;Stephen Hill&lt;/a&gt; (C2O futureplanners), &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gauthier-guerin-6a0a667b/&quot;&gt;Gauthier Guerin&lt;/a&gt; (Catalyst Collective) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-walker-95a23281/&quot;&gt;Stephen Walker&lt;/a&gt; (Oxford Brookes University). Transition by Design provided communication and outreach support for the project.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">In March 2017, Oxford City Council received £54,859 from the Community Housing Fund to support the promotion and delivery of more community-led housing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/190116%20blog%20image-01.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An invitation to our 2018 Annual General Meeting</title><link href="/2018/05/01/an-invite-to-our-agm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An invitation to our 2018 Annual General Meeting" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/05/01/an-invite-to-our-agm</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/05/01/an-invite-to-our-agm.html">&lt;p&gt;Our 2018 Annual General Meeting will be held at Makespace Oxford (Aristotle Lane, Jericho) on 18th June 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-become-a-director-of-oclt&quot;&gt;Want to become a Director of OCLT?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join our merry band of housing boffins all you have to do is get someone to propose you to the board. Applications will be checked before the AGM to make sure candidates meet our criteria and then it will be put to a vote on the evening of the AGM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound good? You can fill out the application here and then email it back to membership@oclt.org.uk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Our 2018 Annual General Meeting will be held at Makespace Oxford (Aristotle Lane, Jericho) on 18th June 2018.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/fields.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet our new Project Manager, John Bloxsom</title><link href="/2018/02/15/meet-our-new-project-officer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet our new Project Manager, John Bloxsom" /><published>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/02/15/meet-our-new-project-officer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/02/15/meet-our-new-project-officer.html">&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the appointment of John Bloxsom to work as a part-time Project Officer with OCLT for at least the next six months. This has been possible due to generous donations by two of our benefactors. Thanks so much to both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John will work on getting the Dean Court project back on track. He will also be working with our collaborators Community First Oxfordshire to pull together the many community-led housing strands across the county and beyond to form a community-led housing network with a view to securing funding to set up an office with expert staff to drive further development of this sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision is to build a vibrant and viable citizen-led housing sector of permanently affordable homes, across the county and beyond. There is government support for this (in the form of grants) at the moment and we need to be positioning ourselves to make the most of this opportunity. It won’t solve the housing crisis but over the course of the next 20 years it can make not only a useful but also a creative and locally meaningful contribution to the housing crisis. A community housing sector will make a creative and locally-meaningful contribution to the housing crisis whilst developing our villages, towns and cities into more viable and vibrant entities with homes for young people and those on average salaries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">We are pleased to announce the appointment of John Bloxsom to work as a part-time Project Officer with OCLT for at least the next six months. This has been possible due to generous donations by two of our benefactors. Thanks so much to both of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/john_bloxsom.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We’re recruiting for a project officer</title><link href="/2017/12/10/recruiting-for-a-project-officer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We’re recruiting for a project officer" /><published>2017-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2017/12/10/recruiting-for-a-project-officer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/12/10/recruiting-for-a-project-officer.html">&lt;p&gt;Oxfordshire Community Land Trust has a vacancy for a Project Officer to work on two very exciting prospects: i) getting our first housing project to the construction phase and ii) working with our Board and partner organisations to create a Community-Led Housing Hub for the county and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be considered for this role please provide a copy of your CV together with a covering statement explaining how you feel you meet the requirements of the role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enquiries and applications to Fran Ryan (Fran.ryan@oclt.org.uk) by close of business Friday 5th January, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviews will take place on Wednesday 10th January 2018 with an aspiration for the successful candidate to start as soon as possible subject to references.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">Oxfordshire Community Land Trust has a vacancy for a Project Officer to work on two very exciting prospects: i) getting our first housing project to the construction phase and ii) working with our Board and partner organisations to create a Community-Led Housing Hub for the county and beyond.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/team.jpg" /></entry></feed>