<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-19T13:04:23+00:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Oxfordshire &lt;br /&gt;Community &lt;br /&gt;Land Trust</title><entry><title type="html">An invitation to our 2018 Annual General Meeting</title><link href="/2018/05/01/an-invite-to-our-agm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An invitation to our 2018 Annual General Meeting" /><published>2018-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/05/01/an-invite-to-our-agm</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/05/01/an-invite-to-our-agm.html">&lt;p&gt;Our 2018 Annual General Meeting will be held at Makespace Oxford (Aristotle Lane, Jericho) on 18th June 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;want-to-become-a-director-of-oclt&quot;&gt;Want to become a Director of OCLT?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To join our merry band of housing boffins all you have to do is get someone to propose you to the board. Applications will be checked before the AGM to make sure candidates meet our criteria and then it will be put to a vote on the evening of the AGM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound good? You can fill out the application here and then email it back to membership@oclt.org.uk.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Our 2018 Annual General Meeting will be held at Makespace Oxford (Aristotle Lane, Jericho) on 18th June 2018.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/fields.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Meet our new Project Manager, John Bloxsom</title><link href="/2018/02/15/meet-our-new-project-officer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meet our new Project Manager, John Bloxsom" /><published>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2018/02/15/meet-our-new-project-officer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/02/15/meet-our-new-project-officer.html">&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce the appointment of John Bloxsom to work as a part-time Project Officer with OCLT for at least the next six months. This has been possible due to generous donations by two of our benefactors. Thanks so much to both of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John will work on getting the Dean Court project back on track. He will also be working with our collaborators Community First Oxfordshire to pull together the many community-led housing strands across the county and beyond to form a community-led housing network with a view to securing funding to set up an office with expert staff to drive further development of this sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vision is to build a vibrant and viable citizen-led housing sector of permanently affordable homes, across the county and beyond. There is government support for this (in the form of grants) at the moment and we need to be positioning ourselves to make the most of this opportunity. It won’t solve the housing crisis but over the course of the next 20 years it can make not only a useful but also a creative and locally meaningful contribution to the housing crisis. A community housing sector will make a creative and locally-meaningful contribution to the housing crisis whilst developing our villages, towns and cities into more viable and vibrant entities with homes for young people and those on average salaries.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">We are pleased to announce the appointment of John Bloxsom to work as a part-time Project Officer with OCLT for at least the next six months. This has been possible due to generous donations by two of our benefactors. Thanks so much to both of them.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/john_bloxsom.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We’re recruiting for a project officer</title><link href="/2017/12/10/recruiting-for-a-project-officer.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We’re recruiting for a project officer" /><published>2017-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/2017/12/10/recruiting-for-a-project-officer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2017/12/10/recruiting-for-a-project-officer.html">&lt;p&gt;Oxfordshire Community Land Trust has a vacancy for a Project Officer to work on two very exciting prospects: i) getting our first housing project to the construction phase and ii) working with our Board and partner organisations to create a Community-Led Housing Hub for the county and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be considered for this role please provide a copy of your CV together with a covering statement explaining how you feel you meet the requirements of the role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enquiries and applications to Fran Ryan (Fran.ryan@oclt.org.uk) by close of business Friday 5th January, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interviews will take place on Wednesday 10th January 2018 with an aspiration for the successful candidate to start as soon as possible subject to references.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><category term="jobs" /><summary type="html">Oxfordshire Community Land Trust has a vacancy for a Project Officer to work on two very exciting prospects: i) getting our first housing project to the construction phase and ii) working with our Board and partner organisations to create a Community-Led Housing Hub for the county and beyond.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/team.jpg" /></entry></feed>